Ajay Chandrasekaran

Front End Engineer

Address Madurai, India 630611 Phone 6381719712 E-mail mail2ajayc@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ajay-in

Passionate and hardworking web developer with nearly 6 years of experience in Front end development. Seeking to leverage my technical and professional expertise and improve my communication and professional IT skills gained through previous experiences in the IT sector.

Technical Profile

- Angular 2 14, Angular Material,
- SCSS, CSS3, HTML5,
- TypeScript, JavaScript
- Git, Perforce
- Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket,
- Agile methodology

Competencies

- Responsive Web Development
- Code Review & Best practices
- Software Development & Documentation
- New employee mentoring

Work History

May 2021 - Current Senior Software Engineer, Light & Wonder formerly Scientific games

- Worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance and customers to resolve technical issues.
- Trained and mentored peers in Angular and frontend practices and working to improve overall team performance.
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations.
- Used understanding of Angular fundamentals to promote better practices, increasing turnaround speed with 100% deadline adherence.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Decreased development time to 50% by overhauling the requirement.
- Remodeled the exciting architecture with the Angular workspace approach to handle complex scenarios.
- Revitalized flash application to angular web application.

December 2019 -May 2021

Senior Engineer, **QBurst**

- Developed a prototype used to visualize different plans in a well-organized manner.
- Built a questionnaire wizard with distinguished animation.
- Balanced requirements, UX, and deadlines in order to get most of the business value in a limited timeframe.
- Engaged In software maintenance across the application.
- Developed and implemented proactive maintenance practices.
- Trained and managed junior engineers.

January 2017 -December 2019

Senior Systems Engineer, Infosys

- Implemented tracking and geo hierarchy from concept.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Collaborated with team members to implement new feature developments.
- Coordinating with back-end developers for integrating API responses to front end

Education

August 2012 -April 2016

CEG, Anna University Chennai Bachelor of Technology Information Technology